<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>New articles in Network Science</title><link>http://antoineallard.info/rss/papers.xml</link><description>New articles in Network Science</description><atom:link href="http://antoineallard.info/rss/papers.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 18:28:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PNAS: Skill networks and measures of complex human capital [Social Sciences]</title><link>http://www.pnas.org/content/114/48/12720.short?rss=1</link><description>We propose a network-based method for measuring worker skills. We illustrate the method using data from an online freelance website. Using the tools of network analysis, we divide skills into endogenous categories based on their relationship with other skills in the market. Workers who specialize in these different areas earn...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">pnas;1706597114</guid></item><item><title>PNAS: Brain network dynamics are hierarchically organized in time [Neuroscience]</title><link>http://www.pnas.org/content/114/48/12827.short?rss=1</link><description>The brain recruits neuronal populations in a temporally coordinated manner in task and at rest. However, the extent to which large-scale networks exhibit their own organized temporal dynamics is unclear. We use an approach designed to find repeating network patterns in whole-brain resting fMRI data, where networks are defined as...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">pnas;1705120114</guid></item><item><title>PNAS: Default mode contributions to automated information processing [Neuroscience]</title><link>http://www.pnas.org/content/114/48/12821.short?rss=1</link><description>Concurrent with mental processes that require rigorous computation and control, a series of automated decisions and actions govern our daily lives, providing efficient and adaptive responses to environmental demands. Using a cognitive flexibility task, we show that a set of brain regions collectively known as the default mode network plays...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">pnas;1710521114</guid></item><item><title>PNAS: Phasic inhibition as a mechanism for generation of rapid respiratory rhythms [Neuroscience]</title><link>http://www.pnas.org/content/114/48/12815.short?rss=1</link><description>Central neural networks operate continuously throughout life to control respiration, yet mechanisms regulating ventilatory frequency are poorly understood. Inspiration is generated by the pre-Bötzinger complex of the ventrolateral medulla, where it is thought that excitation increases inspiratory frequency and inhibition causes apnea. To test this model, we used an in...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">pnas;1711536114</guid></item><item><title>PNAS: Assigning chemoreceptors to chemosensory pathways in Pseudomonas aeruginosa [Microbiology]</title><link>http://www.pnas.org/content/114/48/12809.short?rss=1</link><description>In contrast to Escherichia coli, a model organism for chemotaxis that has 5 chemoreceptors and a single chemosensory pathway, Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1 has a much more complex chemosensory network, which consists of 26 chemoreceptors feeding into four chemosensory pathways. While several chemoreceptors were rigorously linked to specific pathways in a...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">pnas;1708842114</guid></item><item><title>PNAS: Analysis of high-resolution 3D intrachromosomal interactions aided by Bayesian network modeling [Biophysics and Computational Biology]</title><link>http://www.pnas.org/content/114/48/E10359.short?rss=1</link><description>Long-range intrachromosomal interactions play an important role in 3D chromosome structure and function, but our understanding of how various factors contribute to the strength of these interactions remains poor. In this study we used a recently developed analysis framework for Bayesian network (BN) modeling to analyze publicly available datasets for...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">pnas;1620425114</guid></item><item><title>PNAS: Converging evidence for the role of transmodal cortex in cognition [Neuroscience]</title><link>http://www.pnas.org/content/114/48/12641.short?rss=1</link><description>The studies by Vidaurre et al. (1) and Vatansever et al. (2) in PNAS provide contrasting, yet complementary insights into the role that regions of transmodal cortex, including those in the default mode network (DMN) (3) and the fronto-parietal network (FPN) (4), play in cognition. Vatansever et al. (2) used...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">pnas;1717374114</guid></item><item><title>Phys. Rev. X: Sensitive Dependence of Optimal Network Dynamics on Network Structure</title><link>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.7.041044</link><description>Author(s): Takashi Nishikawa, Jie Sun, and Adilson E. Motter&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The relationship between the structure and dynamics of a network is key to understanding the behavior of complex systems. A new analysis shows how network optimization, whether designed or evolved, can lead to collective dynamics that depend sensitively on the structure of the network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="//d22izw7byeupn1.cloudfront.net/journals/PRX/key_images/10.1103/PhysRevX.7.041044.png" width="200" height=\"100\"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[Phys. Rev. X 7, 041044] Published Tue Nov 28, 2017</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10.1103/PhysRevX.7.041044</guid></item><item><title>Phys. Rev. E: Finding multiple core-periphery pairs in networks</title><link>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.96.052313</link><description>Author(s): Sadamori Kojaku and Naoki Masuda&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a core-periphery structure of networks, core nodes are densely interconnected, peripheral nodes are connected to core nodes to different extents, and peripheral nodes are sparsely interconnected. Core-periphery structure composed of a single core and periphery has been identified for various ne...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[Phys. Rev. E 96, 052313] Published Wed Nov 22, 2017</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10.1103/PhysRevE.96.052313</guid></item><item><title>Phys. Rev. E: Unified mean-field framework for susceptible-infected-susceptible epidemics on networks, based on graph partitioning and the isoperimetric inequality</title><link>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.96.052314</link><description>Author(s): K. Devriendt and P. Van Mieghem&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We propose an approximation framework that unifies and generalizes a number of existing mean-field approximation methods for the susceptible-infected-susceptible (SIS) epidemic model on complex networks. We derive the framework, which we call the unified mean-field framework (UMFF), as a set of appr...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[Phys. Rev. E 96, 052314] Published Mon Nov 27, 2017</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10.1103/PhysRevE.96.052314</guid></item><item><title>Phys. Rev. E: Zealotry effects on opinion dynamics in the adaptive voter model</title><link>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.96.052315</link><description>Author(s): Pascal P. Klamser, Marc Wiedermann, Jonathan F. Donges, and Reik V. Donner&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The adaptive voter model has been widely studied as a conceptual model for opinion formation processes on time-evolving social networks. Past studies on the effect of zealots, i.e., nodes aiming to spread their fixed opinion throughout the system, only considered the voter model on a static network....&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[Phys. Rev. E 96, 052315] Published Tue Nov 28, 2017</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10.1103/PhysRevE.96.052315</guid></item><item><title>Sci. Adv.: Climate change and water management in the biblical city of Dan</title><link>http://advances.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/short/3/11/e1700954?rss=1</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Global climate change has sharpened focus on the social and economic challenges associated with water deficits, particularly in regions where anthropogenic demands exceed supply. This modern condition was also experienced by the people of ancient western Asia, where chronic water shortages were accentuated by recurrent droughts. However, human societies may react to climate change, particularly desiccation, in different ways depending on specific local conditions. Focusing on the biblical site of Tel Dan (present-day Israel), we show the effects of severe precipitation decline in an environment that was well watered and fertile even in times of drought. Such local niches of prosperity became attractive targets for predation when food resources became scarce in surrounding rain-fed areas. We propose that predation forced urban populations to either flee or adopt new subsistence strategies. Predation and abandonment, even if only partial, led to the poor maintenance of water networks in and around the city. Once stagnant water surrounded the area, water-borne disease proliferated. Our study shows how climate changes can disrupt social and political structures, cause water system management to collapse, and facilitate marshland expansion.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">advances;3/11/e1700954</guid></item><item><title>Sci. Adv.: Networks of global bird invasion altered by regional trade ban</title><link>http://advances.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/short/3/11/e1700783?rss=1</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wildlife trade is a major pathway for introduction of invasive species worldwide. However, how exactly wildlife trade influences invasion risk, beyond the transportation of individuals to novel areas, remains unknown. We analyze the global trade network of wild-caught birds from 1995 to 2011 as reported by CITES (Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora). We found that before the European Union ban on imports of wild-caught birds, declared in 2005, invasion risk was closely associated with numbers of imported birds, diversity of import sources, and degree of network centrality of importer countries. After the ban, fluxes of global bird trade declined sharply. However, new trade routes emerged, primarily toward the Nearctic, Afrotropical, and Indo-Malay regions. Although regional bans can curtail invasion risk globally, to be fully effective and prevent rerouting of trade flows, bans should be global.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">advances;3/11/e1700783</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Photonic quantum state transfer between a cold atomic gas and a crystal</title><link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/nature/rss/current/~3/9Wx3jMYjBZg/nature24468</link><description>Interfacing fundamentally different quantum systems is key to building future hybrid quantum networks. Such heterogeneous networks offer capabilities superior to those of their homogeneous counterparts, as they merge the individual advantages of disparate quantum nodes in a single network architecture. However, few investigations of optical hybrid interconnections have been carried out, owing to fundamental and technological challenges such as wavelength and bandwidth matching of the interfacing photons. Here we report optical quantum interconnection of two disparate matter quantum systems with photon storage capabilities. We show that a quantum state can be transferred faithfully between a cold atomic ensemble and a rare-earth-doped crystal by means of a single photon at 1,552  nanometre telecommunication wavelength, using cascaded quantum frequency conversion. We demonstrate that quantum correlations between a photon and a single collective spin excitation in the cold atomic ensemble can be transferred to the solid-state system. We also show that single-photon time-bin qubits generated in the cold atomic ensemble can be converted, stored and retrieved from the crystal with a conditional qubit fidelity of more than 85 per cent. Our results open up the prospect of optically connecting quantum nodes with different capabilities and represent an important step towards the realization of large-scale hybrid quantum networks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10.1038/nature24468</guid></item><item><title>Nature: The internet that wasn’t</title><link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/nature/rss/current/~3/odb6qLN7IyU/d41586-017-07220-w</link><description>Sharon Weinberger weighs up a history of PLATO, a prescient but doomed 1960s US computer network.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10.1038/d41586-017-07220-w</guid></item></channel></rss>